<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 22:50:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing Nerd Font in Termux: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/nerd-font-termux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 22:50:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/nerd-font-termux/</guid>
      <description>Termux is a popular terminal emulator app for Android devices that allows users to run a variety of Linux tools on their mobile devices. However, by default, Termux uses a plain font, which can be less visually appealing.
Enter Nerd Fonts, a collection of specially designed fonts that adds extra characters and symbols to the standard font. Nerd Fonts are ideal for developers and power users who want to make their terminal experience more visually appealing and easier to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Apps Using Terminal in Ubuntu 22.10</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/10-how-to-install-apps-using-terminal-in-ubuntu-22.10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 04:38:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/10-how-to-install-apps-using-terminal-in-ubuntu-22.10/</guid>
      <description>Using terminal is the easiest way to install apps in linux
Installing appsTo install apps use the following command:
$ sudo apt install packageName Replace packageName with the name of the package
Uninstalling appsUsing removeTo uninstall apps use the following command:
$ sudo apt remove packageNamudo/ Replace packageName with the name of the package
or
Using purge$ sudo apt purge packageName Replace packageName with the name of the package
Difference between remove &amp;amp; purgeThe primary difference being ‘remove‘ and ‘purge‘ is that ‘remove‘ only gets rid of the package leaving any configuration files untouched.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
