<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>llvm on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/llvm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in llvm on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 22:07:24 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/llvm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 19 &amp; 20 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-19-20-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 22:07:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-19-20-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>These couple of weeks have been very hectic as my college has started and campus placements have started as well so I have been busy with that as well.&#xA;Progress Added submenu for navbar which is configurable. Created table of contents component. Created /gsoc-projects page using yaml data file. Created a custom shortcode for creating new pages using data files. Wrote stylesheet for standard markdown pages. Wrote some documentation for creating new pages in the website using datamap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 18 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-18-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 11:02:38 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-18-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I set up a website in a new repository using the theme developed. I fixed some UI bugs and made the hero section links configurable. I also wrote documentation for the theme and set up a workflow for deploying using GitHub Pages.&#xA;The website is live at https://chaitanyashahare.com/testing-llvm-www-template for now. We are in the process of hosting it on the llvm.org test sub-domain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 17 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-17-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:21:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-17-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I deployed a website created using the theme developed, on GitHub pages. The website&amp;rsquo;s home page at my domain for testing here https://chaitanyashahare.com/testing-llvm-www-template.&#xA;Working on making the footer configurable as it&amp;rsquo;ll vary a lot across websites. The footer will be configurable from the hugo.yml configuration file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 16 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-16-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 10:02:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-16-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I completed making the navbar menu responsive, and the navbar items can now be configured using hugo.yml.&#xA;I had limited time this week as I was moving back to college, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t make much progress. I&amp;rsquo;m done with the navbar and made it work on mobile. The navbar items are now configurable from the configuration file.&#xA;Navbar Menu 🍔I made the navbar menu responsive this week. The navbar items are now configurable from the hugo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 15 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-15-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 12:29:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-15-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I completed the theme switcher and made the website responsive. I am now working on adding a navbar menu to the website.&#xA;Video demo Theme Switcher 🌈I completed the theme switcher this week. The theme switcher allows users to switch between light and dark themes on the website. Users can now choose the theme they prefer for the website.&#xA;It also detects the user&amp;rsquo;s system preference for light or dark mode and sets the theme accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 14 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-14-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 12:25:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-14-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I implemented the home page design and am now focusing on mobile responsiveness and adding a theme switcher.&#xA;I had a doubt I wanted to discuss with my mentors about the GitHub repository where I can raise a pull request.&#xA;Home Page Design 🏠I completed the home page design this week. The design includes the layout of the home page with the sections and the content to be displayed on the home page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 13 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-13-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 22:39:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-13-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I drafted an abstract for the LLVM Developers&amp;rsquo; Meeting proposal. I also made changes to the design layout according to the feedback in another design file so as not to tamper with the feedback form.&#xA;LLVM Developers&amp;rsquo; Meeting Proposal 📝I drafted an abstract for the LLVM Developers&amp;rsquo; Meeting proposal for a talk. The proposal includes the abstract describing the talk, the target audience, and the key takeaways from the talk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 12 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-12-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 22:38:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-12-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I iterated on the feedback form for design mockups and circulated it in the community. I also prepared the midterm progress presentation.&#xA;Feedback Form 📝I iterated on the feedback form for design mockups based on the feedback received from my mentors. I made the form more detailed and focused on the layout of the website.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the feedback form: LLVM Website Redesign Feedback Form</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 11 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-11-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 22:58:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-11-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I presented the project in LLVM&amp;rsquo;s GSoC mini-conference. I also started working on making padding consistent on the Compiler Research website. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting on Tanya for the review of the feedback form.&#xA;Presentation 🎤I presented the LLVM.org website redesign project in the LLVM&amp;rsquo;s GSoC mini-conference. The presentation included the progress made so far, the design mockup, and the feedback form for the design mockup. The presentation went well, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get any feedback on my work as there was limited time and we were just given 3 - 5 minutes to present our project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-10-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 22:50:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-10-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I worked on enhancing the design mockup inspired by the Swift website. I also created a feedback form for the current design mockup. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress.&#xA;Design Enhancements 🎨I made some enhancements to the design mockup inspired by the Swift website. The changes include:&#xA;Improved the color scheme and styling. Added a new section for the latest news and updates. Consistent typography across the website.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 9 of Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-9-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-9-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This week I created the 3rd design mockup of the LLVM website. I also worked on the implementation of the design using HTML and CSS. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress.&#xA;Designing Mockups 🎨I created the 3rd design mockup of the LLVM website. This design is inspired by the Swift website.&#xA;Also created the dark mode version of the design.&#xA;Here are the links to that design:&#xA;Light Mode: Design Mockup Dark Mode: Design Mockup Feedback and Improvements 🚀Drafted a feedback form for the design mockups focused on the following aspects:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 7 &amp; 8 of Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-7-8-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:38:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-7-8-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Week 7 and 8 of my Google Summer of Code clashed with my End Semester Examinations of 6th Semester.&#xA;I had to take a break from my GSoC work to focus on my exams.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 6 of Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-6-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 19:18:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-6-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Week 6 of my Google Summer of Code was focused on desiging mockups for the LLVM website. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress.&#xA;Designing Mockups 🎨I spent most of my time this week designing mockups for the LLVM website. I created mockups for the homepage with 2 different designs. 1 is inspired from the Rust website and the other is inspired from the the MLIR website which is a part of the LLVM ecosystem so there are a high chance that the LLVM community likes it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 at GSoC @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-5-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 22:30:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-5-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Week 5 of my Google Summer of Code journey redesigning the LLVM webite has been pretty slow but did some work on the Compiler Research website. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress.&#xA;Survey Responses 📊I didn&amp;rsquo;t get any more responses on the survey this week. I discussed with my mentor regarding this and he suggested that we move on to the further steps without waiting for any more responses.&#xA;Designing Mockups 🎨I haven&amp;rsquo;t made any progress on the design mockups this week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 at GSoC @ LLVM: Getting a few responses on survey</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-4-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 21:37:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-4-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Week 4 of my Google Summer of Code journey with LLVM.org has been pretty exciting. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress.&#xA;Survey Responses 📊This week I got some responses on the survey I had sent out last week. 43 to be exact. That&amp;rsquo;s not a lot but it&amp;rsquo;s a good start.&#xA;The RFC and the survey was discussed in the LLVM Weekly meeting and newsletter, so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting a lot more responses in the coming few weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 at Google Summer of Code @LLVM.org: Releasing the RFC and Finalizing the Survey</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-3-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 21:44:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-3-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone!&#xA;Week 3 of my Google Summer of Code journey with LLVM.org has been both productive and pivotal. Here’s an update on my progress, including releasing the RFC, finalizing the community survey, and enhancing the LLVM.org blog.&#xA;Releasing the RFCOne of the significant milestones this week was releasing the Request for Comments (RFC) on the LLVM discourse forum. The RFC outlines the proposed redesign of the LLVM.org website, detailing the goals, changes, and expected outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 at Google Summer of Code @LLVM.org: Progress and Presentations</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-2-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 21:38:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-2-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone!&#xA;Week 2 of my Google Summer of Code journey at LLVM.org has been both productive and engaging. Here’s a quick recap of the progress made and key activities from this week.&#xA;Advancing the ProjectThis week, I focused on completing the first drafts of the Request for Comments (RFC) and the community survey. These documents are crucial for conducting a preliminary content audit and gathering community feedback on the LLVM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 at Google Summer of Code @LLVM.org: Kicking Off the Community Bonding Period</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-1-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 11:25:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-1-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone!&#xA;It’s been an exhilarating first week at Google Summer of Code 2024, where I’ve begun my journey to revamp the LLVM.org website. As I dive into the world of open-source development at such a large scale, everything feels new and exciting. Here’s a breakdown of my first week, the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made, and what I’ve learned along the way.&#xA;Diving InThe week started with an orientation session where I got to meet other GSoC participants from around the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLVM.org Website Redesign GSoC Project Introduction</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/llvm-org-website-redesign-gsoc-project-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 09:59:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/llvm-org-website-redesign-gsoc-project-introduction/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionI’m Chaitanya Shahare, a passionate full-stack web developer and a pre-final-year Mechanical Engineering student at the National Institute of Technology Srinagar, India. This summer, I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to embark on an exciting journey with LLVM as Google Summer of Code 2024 contributor, where I&amp;rsquo;ll be contributing to the LLVM project by improving the look and feel of its central hub, the LLVM.org website.&#xA;Mentors: Tanya Lattner and Vassil Vassilev&#xA;Why I Chose LLVM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Got Accepted in Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2024!!!</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/i-got-accepted-in-google-summer-of-code-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 20:25:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/i-got-accepted-in-google-summer-of-code-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>I am very delighted to announce that I have been accepted into Google Summer of Code 2024! It&amp;rsquo;s an incredible opportunity, and I&amp;rsquo;m beyond excited to be a part of this enriching experience. For those who may not be familiar, Google Summer of Code (GSoC) is a global program that connects students with open source software organizations to work on a summer programming project under the guidance of experienced mentors.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
