<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>macos on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/categories/macos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in macos on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 02:03:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/categories/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Map Capslock to Escape Key in MacOS Ventura</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-map-capslock-to-escape-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 02:03:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-map-capslock-to-escape-key/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionIn my opinion, Caps Lock is the most useless key on the keyboard I&amp;rsquo;ve never used it.
But the Escape key is the most useful key especially for Vim users.
How to Map Caps Lock to Escape Key in MacOS Open System Preferences Go to Keyboard Click on Modifier Keys Select Caps Lock Key and change it to Escape And its done. Now you can use Caps Lock as Escape key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to SSH into MacOS from another device</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/ssh-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 23:09:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/ssh-macos/</guid>
      <description>SSH (Secure Shell) is a protocol used for secure communication between two devices over a network. It is commonly used to connect to remote servers or to control other devices. In this article, I will show you how to SSH into a macOS device from another device, such as a Windows PC, Linux machine, or another macOS device.
Step 1: Enable SSH on the Target macOS DeviceFirst, you need to enable SSH on the target macOS device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download YouTube videos from terminal using youtube-dl on MacOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/youtube-dl-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 12:03:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/youtube-dl-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>youtube-dl is a terminal application which lets you download YouTube videos easily without ads and other bloat, unlike other YouTube video downloaders online.
PrerequisitesHomeBrew Install brew using the official HomeBrew Installation instructions Go ahead if already installed Installing youtube-dlTo install youtube-dl using brew, run the following command in the MacOS terminal:
brew install youtube-dl Downloading videosTo download YouTube videos using youtube-dl, use the following command:
youtube-dl &amp;#39;youtube-url&amp;#39; Make sure to use quotes around the URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Intall MySQL on MacOS using HomeBrew </title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/mysql-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:46:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/mysql-installation/</guid>
      <description>PrerequisitesHomeBrew Install brew using the official HomeBrew Installation instructions Go ahead if already installed Installing MySQLTo install MySQL, run the following command in your MacOS terminal:
brew install mysql Running MySQLTo start MySQL server, run the following command:
brew services start mysql VerifyingTo check whether MySQL server is running, run the following command:
brew services list Usagemysql -u root PasswordFor setting Password and other configuration, run the following command after MySQL server has started</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install MongoDB 6.0 on MacOS </title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/mongodb-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 07:22:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/mongodb-installation/</guid>
      <description>These instructions are for MongoDB 6.0 Community Edition
PrerequisitesHomeBrew Install brew using the official HomeBrew Installation instructions Go ahead if already installed Installing MongoDB 6.0 Community Edition Tap the MongoDB Homebrew Tap to download the official Homebrew formula for MongoDB and the Database Tools, by running the following command in your macOS Terminal:
brew tap mongodb/brew To update Homebrew and all existing formulae:
brew update To install MongoDB, run the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make MacOS Terminal Beautiful With Background Image</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-make-macos-terminal-beautiful-with-background-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 22:42:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-make-macos-terminal-beautiful-with-background-image/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionMacOS&amp;rsquo;s default Terminal as of it is, is pretty boring and not very good to look at.
It&amp;rsquo;s just some text on a solid background.
The easiest way to customise your terminal is to add a background.
Following are the steps for the same:
Install Iterm2Iterm2 is a terminal emulator, does everything the default Terminal does and more.
https://iterm2.com
TransparencyIterm -&amp;gt; Preferences -&amp;gt; Profiles -&amp;gt; Window -&amp;gt; Transparency
Full screenIterm Preferences -&amp;gt; General -&amp;gt; Window -&amp;gt; Native full screen windows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to hide split pane title bars in Iterm2 MacOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-hide-split-pane-title-bars-in-iterm2-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 23:53:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-hide-split-pane-title-bars-in-iterm2-macos/</guid>
      <description>StepsIterm2 preferences -&amp;gt; Appearance -&amp;gt; Panes -&amp;gt; toggle off show per-pane title bar
Before After Other tips Split pane shortcuts Cmd + d - for splitting window vertically Cmd + Shift + d - for splitting window horizontally References Iterm2 Documentation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Merge PDFs in MacOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/12-how-to-merge-pdfs-in-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 17:50:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/12-how-to-merge-pdfs-in-macos/</guid>
      <description>You can merge PDFs right in the MacOS finder
Have all PDFs in a folderMake sure you have all the PDFs you want to merge in the same directory
Select the filesYou can select multiple files by CMD + Click
Merge files Right Click and hover on Quick Actions Click on Create PDF New merged PDF is now created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Alacritty on MacOS Ventura</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/11-how-to-install-alacritty-on-macos-ventura/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 15:34:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/11-how-to-install-alacritty-on-macos-ventura/</guid>
      <description>Alacritty is a modern terminal emulator that comes with sensible defaults, but allows for extensive configuration.
Unlike iterm2 for MacOS, Alacritty doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any kind of GUI for it&amp;rsquo;s configuration. Everything can be done using a conf file.
Installing using HomebrewUse the following brew command in terminal:
$ brew install --cask alacritty Launching Alacritty When launching alacritty for the first time, there might be a pop up similar to - To fix this you can use the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
