<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utility on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/utility/</link>
    <description>Recent content in utility on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 02:03:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/utility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Map Capslock to Escape Key in MacOS Ventura</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-map-capslock-to-escape-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 02:03:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-map-capslock-to-escape-key/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionIn my opinion, Caps Lock is the most useless key on the keyboard I&amp;rsquo;ve never used it.
But the Escape key is the most useful key especially for Vim users.
How to Map Caps Lock to Escape Key in MacOS Open System Preferences Go to Keyboard Click on Modifier Keys Select Caps Lock Key and change it to Escape And its done. Now you can use Caps Lock as Escape key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream Your Media Content with Ease: How to Install Jellyfin on Ubuntu 22.04</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/jellyfin-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/jellyfin-installation/</guid>
      <description>Jellyfin is a free and open-source media server that allows you to stream your media content like music, videos, and images to various devices. It supports multiple operating systems, including Ubuntu 22.04. In this guide, we will walk you through the process of installing Jellyfin on Ubuntu 22.04.
Step 1: Update the SystemBefore installing any new software on your Ubuntu system, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to ensure that your system is up-to-date. To update your Ubuntu system, open the terminal by pressing Ctrl + Alt + T or by searching for the terminal in the applications menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download YouTube videos from terminal using youtube-dl on MacOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/youtube-dl-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 12:03:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/youtube-dl-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>youtube-dl is a terminal application which lets you download YouTube videos easily without ads and other bloat, unlike other YouTube video downloaders online.
PrerequisitesHomeBrew Install brew using the official HomeBrew Installation instructions Go ahead if already installed Installing youtube-dlTo install youtube-dl using brew, run the following command in the MacOS terminal:
brew install youtube-dl Downloading videosTo download YouTube videos using youtube-dl, use the following command:
youtube-dl &amp;#39;youtube-url&amp;#39; Make sure to use quotes around the URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Merge PDFs in MacOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/12-how-to-merge-pdfs-in-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 17:50:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/12-how-to-merge-pdfs-in-macos/</guid>
      <description>You can merge PDFs right in the MacOS finder
Have all PDFs in a folderMake sure you have all the PDFs you want to merge in the same directory
Select the filesYou can select multiple files by CMD + Click
Merge files Right Click and hover on Quick Actions Click on Create PDF New merged PDF is now created.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
