<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 16:43:54 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Change VS Code Terminal Position to Right Side for a Neat Workspace</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/post/how-to-change-vscode-terminal-position-to-right-pane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 16:43:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/post/how-to-change-vscode-terminal-position-to-right-pane/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionVisual Studio Code is a great editor for developers. It has a lot of features and extensions that make it a great choice for developers. One of the features that I like the most is the integrated terminal. It is very useful for running commands and scripts without leaving the editor.
But the default position of the terminal is at the bottom of the editor. This is not a good position for the terminal as it takes up a lot of space and makes the editor look cluttered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Built My First Vscode Extension: Lazygit for VS Code</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/post/how-i-built-my-first-vscode-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 13:29:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/post/how-i-built-my-first-vscode-plugin/</guid>
      <description>Introduction https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ChaitanyaShahare.lazygit
My journey with Visual Studio Code (VS Code) has been on and off ever since I started to code, you can read more about that here.
But for some or the other reason I keep coming back to it. I feel that the only reason I think that I&amp;rsquo;m faster in neovim is the customisability of it, the ability to do anything as I like to do. Not getting adapted to the workflows but creating them as they are suited to me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
