<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workflow on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in workflow on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 06:31:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Effortless MacOS Desktop Navigation: Boost Your Productivity and Master Your Workflow</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-navigate-macos-desktops-like-a-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 06:31:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-navigate-macos-desktops-like-a-pro/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionAny one who has used a mac knows that the whole MacOS experience revolves around the concept of desktops. Desktops are a way to organize your workflow, and keep your work organized.
The problem is that most people don&amp;rsquo;t use desktops to their full potential. Most of us rely on multiple 3-finger swipes on the trackpad to navigate to the desktop we want.
In this blog post, I will show you some shortcuts that you can enable to make this process effortless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Your Productivity: Create a Schedule with ChatGPT and Sync it with Google Calendar</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/maximise-your-productivity-create-a-schedule-with-chatgpt-and-sync-it-with-google-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 15:00:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/maximise-your-productivity-create-a-schedule-with-chatgpt-and-sync-it-with-google-calendar/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionPlanning ahead is arguably the most important skill for being more productive. Nothing notable can be accomplished without a plan. A daily schedule can help you achieve your goals and remove the stress of wondering what to do next.
With a good plan and schedule, you can sit back and relax when it&amp;rsquo;s time to relax and get things done when you&amp;rsquo;ve planned it. You can be assured that you have adequate time for all your commitments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
