<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>opensource on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/opensource/</link>
    <description>Recent content in opensource on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 19:18:57 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/opensource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 6 of Google Summer of Code @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-6-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 19:18:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-6-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Week 6 of my Google Summer of Code was focused on desiging mockups for the LLVM website. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress.&#xA;Designing Mockups 🎨I spent most of my time this week designing mockups for the LLVM website. I created mockups for the homepage with 2 different designs. 1 is inspired from the Rust website and the other is inspired from the the MLIR website which is a part of the LLVM ecosystem so there are a high chance that the LLVM community likes it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 at GSoC @ LLVM</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-5-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 22:30:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-5-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Week 5 of my Google Summer of Code journey redesigning the LLVM webite has been pretty slow but did some work on the Compiler Research website. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress.&#xA;Survey Responses 📊I didn&amp;rsquo;t get any more responses on the survey this week. I discussed with my mentor regarding this and he suggested that we move on to the further steps without waiting for any more responses.&#xA;Designing Mockups 🎨I haven&amp;rsquo;t made any progress on the design mockups this week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 at GSoC @ LLVM: Getting a few responses on survey</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-4-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 21:37:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-4-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Week 4 of my Google Summer of Code journey with LLVM.org has been pretty exciting. Here&amp;rsquo;s an update on my progress.&#xA;Survey Responses 📊This week I got some responses on the survey I had sent out last week. 43 to be exact. That&amp;rsquo;s not a lot but it&amp;rsquo;s a good start.&#xA;The RFC and the survey was discussed in the LLVM Weekly meeting and newsletter, so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting a lot more responses in the coming few weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 at Google Summer of Code @LLVM.org: Releasing the RFC and Finalizing the Survey</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-3-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 21:44:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-3-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone!&#xA;Week 3 of my Google Summer of Code journey with LLVM.org has been both productive and pivotal. Here’s an update on my progress, including releasing the RFC, finalizing the community survey, and enhancing the LLVM.org blog.&#xA;Releasing the RFCOne of the significant milestones this week was releasing the Request for Comments (RFC) on the LLVM discourse forum. The RFC outlines the proposed redesign of the LLVM.org website, detailing the goals, changes, and expected outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 at Google Summer of Code @LLVM.org: Progress and Presentations</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-2-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 21:38:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-2-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone!&#xA;Week 2 of my Google Summer of Code journey at LLVM.org has been both productive and engaging. Here’s a quick recap of the progress made and key activities from this week.&#xA;Advancing the ProjectThis week, I focused on completing the first drafts of the Request for Comments (RFC) and the community survey. These documents are crucial for conducting a preliminary content audit and gathering community feedback on the LLVM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 at Google Summer of Code @LLVM.org: Kicking Off the Community Bonding Period</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-1-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 11:25:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/week-1-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone!&#xA;It’s been an exhilarating first week at Google Summer of Code 2024, where I’ve begun my journey to revamp the LLVM.org website. As I dive into the world of open-source development at such a large scale, everything feels new and exciting. Here’s a breakdown of my first week, the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made, and what I’ve learned along the way.&#xA;Diving InThe week started with an orientation session where I got to meet other GSoC participants from around the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Got Accepted in Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2024!!!</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/i-got-accepted-in-google-summer-of-code-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 20:25:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/i-got-accepted-in-google-summer-of-code-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>I am very delighted to announce that I have been accepted into Google Summer of Code 2024! It&amp;rsquo;s an incredible opportunity, and I&amp;rsquo;m beyond excited to be a part of this enriching experience. For those who may not be familiar, Google Summer of Code (GSoC) is a global program that connects students with open source software organizations to work on a summer programming project under the guidance of experienced mentors.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
