<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in git on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 20:27:44 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git Interactive Rebase Is Amazing</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/git-interactive-rebase-is-amazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 20:27:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/git-interactive-rebase-is-amazing/</guid>
      <description>If you are like me and just at the start of your coding journey, git rebase --interactive might be a scary command. I feared that if anything went wrong I would lose a lot of my code and have to do that work all over again.&#xA;But that was the point of using a version control system like git, to not worry about changing your code. Git is here to save our code not to destroy it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essential GitLab CLI Commands for Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/gitlab-cli-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 22:16:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/gitlab-cli-command/</guid>
      <description>GitLab, a popular platform for collaborative software development, offers a robust suite of tools to manage your repositories, CI/CD pipelines, and more. Among these tools, the GitLab CLI (Command Line Interface), known as glab, is a powerful asset that can streamline your workflow. Whether you’re an experienced developer or a newcomer, mastering glab can significantly boost your productivity. This blog post will guide you through the most useful glab commands to enhance your development process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essential GitHub CLI Commands for Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/github-cli-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:13:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/github-cli-command/</guid>
      <description>GitHub, the cornerstone of collaborative software development, offers an extensive ecosystem of tools. Among them, the GitHub CLI (Command Line Interface) stands out as a powerful ally in streamlining your development workflow. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned developer or a beginner, mastering the GitHub CLI can drastically speed up your operations, from repository management to issue tracking. This blog post will guide you through the most useful GitHub CLI commands to enhance your productivity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Git Merge vs. Git Rebase: A Guide for Beginners and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/git-merge-vs-rebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 21:49:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/git-merge-vs-rebase/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionGit is a powerful tool for version control, enabling teams and individuals to track changes, collaborate, and manage code effectively. Two of the most commonly used commands in Git are git merge and git rebase. Both commands are instrumental in integrating changes from one branch into another, but they do so in different ways that can significantly affect the project history and the overall workflow. This blog post aims to demystify these commands for beginners while providing valuable insights for more experienced users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of Multiple GitHub Accounts: Mastering Terminal Configuration</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/manage-multiple-github-accounts-in-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 08:55:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/manage-multiple-github-accounts-in-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:Using multiple GitHub accounts is a common scenario for developers who work on personal and professional projects simultaneously. However, managing these accounts within your terminal can be a bit tricky. In this guide, I will walk you through the process of adding multiple GitHub accounts to your terminal and configuring them correctly, ensuring a seamless experience when working on different projects. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and learn how to manage multiple GitHub accounts effortlessly.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
