<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neovim on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/categories/neovim/</link>
    <description>Recent content in neovim on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 21:41:45 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/categories/neovim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Effortless Case-Insensitive Searching in Vim and Neovim</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/case-insensitive-searching-in-vim-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 21:41:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/case-insensitive-searching-in-vim-neovim/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionVim and Neovim are powerful text editors, and efficient searching is a crucial skill for every user. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive straight into the valuable world of case-insensitive searching, allowing you to find text without worrying about letter case. Whether you use Vim or Neovim, this tip is for you.
Enabling Case-Insensitive Search1. Ignoring CaseTo enable case-insensitive searching in Vim or Neovim, type the following command:
:set ignorecase Now Vim or Neovim will search without considering letter case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Copy and Paste From System Clipboard in Vim and Neovim</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-copy-and-paste-from-system-clipboard-in-vim-and-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 20:48:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-copy-and-paste-from-system-clipboard-in-vim-and-neovim/</guid>
      <description>CommandTo copy and paste from system clipboard in Vim and Neovim, you can use the following command:
set clipboard=unnamedplus You can write in the ~/.vimrc for Vim or ~/.config/nvim/init.vim for Neovim file to make it permanent.
set clipboard=unnamedplus Usage Copied text on your system clipboard can be pasted in Vim or Neovim using p or P command. Text can be copied from Vim or Neovim using y command and pasted in any other application with ctrl + v or cmd + v.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
