<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 12:03:35 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Download YouTube videos from terminal using youtube-dl on MacOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/youtube-dl-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 12:03:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/youtube-dl-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Youtube-dl is a terminal application which lets you download youtube videos easily without ads and other bloat, unlike other youtube video downloaders online.
PrerequisitesHomeBrew Install brew using the official HomeBrew Installation instructions Go ahead if already installed Installing youtube-dlTo install youtube-dl using brew, run the following command in the MacOS terminal:
brew install youtube-dl Downloading videosTo download youtube videos using youtube-dl, use the following command:
youtube-dl &amp;#39;youtube-url&amp;#39; Resources $ man youtube-dl youtube-dl Official Site </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Intall MySQL on MacOS using HomeBrew </title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/mysql-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:46:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/mysql-installation/</guid>
      <description>PrerequisitesHomeBrew Install brew using the official HomeBrew Installation instructions Go ahead if already installed Installing MySQLTo install MySQL, run the following command in your MacOS terminal:
brew install mysql Running MySQLTo start MySQL server, run the following command:
brew services start mysql VerifyingTo check whether MySQL server is running, run the following command:
brew services list Usagemysql -u root PasswordFor setting Password and other configuration, run the following command after MySQL server has started</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install MongoDB 6.0 on MacOS </title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/mongodb-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 07:22:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/mongodb-installation/</guid>
      <description>These instructions are for MongoDB 6.0 Community Edition
PrerequisitesHomeBrew Install brew using the official HomeBrew Installation instructions Go ahead if already installed Installing MongoDB 6.0 Community Edition Tap the MongoDB Homebrew Tap to download the official Homebrew formula for MongoDB and the Database Tools, by running the following command in your macOS Terminal:
brew tap mongodb/brew To update Homebrew and all existing formulae:
brew update To install MongoDB, run the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make a new React Project</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/new-react-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:42:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/new-react-project/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisitesnodejs &amp;amp; npm must be installed
create-react-appUse the following command in the terminal
$ npx create-react-app dirName This creates a directory with the name &amp;lsquo;dirName&amp;rsquo;, which has all the necessary files for a react project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make MacOS Terminal Beautiful With Background Image</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-make-macos-terminal-beautiful-with-background-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 22:42:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-make-macos-terminal-beautiful-with-background-image/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionMacOS&amp;rsquo;s default Terminal as of it is, is pretty boring and not very good to look at.
It&amp;rsquo;s just some text on a solid background.
The easiest way to customise your terminal is to add a background.
Following are the steps for the same:
Install Iterm2Iterm2 is a terminal emulator, does everything the default Terminal does and more.
https://iterm2.com
TransparencyIterm -&amp;gt; Preferences -&amp;gt; Profiles -&amp;gt; Window -&amp;gt; Transparency
Full screenIterm Preferences -&amp;gt; General -&amp;gt; Window -&amp;gt; Native full screen windows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to hide split pane title bars in Iterm2 MacOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-hide-split-pane-title-bars-in-iterm2-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 23:53:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/how-to-hide-split-pane-title-bars-in-iterm2-macos/</guid>
      <description>StepsIterm2 preferences -&amp;gt; Appearance -&amp;gt; Panes -&amp;gt; toggle off show per-pane title bar
Before After Other tips Split pane shortcuts Cmd + d - for splitting window vertically Cmd + Shift + d - for splitting window horizontally References Iterm2 Documentation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to learn Touchtyping</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/13-how-i-learnt-to-touchtype/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 19:15:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/13-how-i-learnt-to-touchtype/</guid>
      <description>What is Touchtyping?Touchtyping is a method of typing which requires you to use all 10 fingers and makes typing on a keyboard more than just finding &amp;amp; pressing buttons. It makes you blazing fast &amp;amp; efficient.
Touchtyping is a great skill, it can literally save you a lot of time looking for different keys when you need it.
But it can be a little intimidating and frustrating to start learning a new way of typing just like anyting new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Merge PDFs in MacOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/12-how-to-merge-pdfs-in-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 17:50:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/12-how-to-merge-pdfs-in-macos/</guid>
      <description>You can merge PDFs right in the MacOS finder
Have all PDFs in a folderMake sure you have all the PDFs you want to merge in the same directory
Select the filesYou can select multiple files by CMD + Click
Merge files Right Click and hover on Quick Actions Click on Create PDF New merged PDF is now created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Alacritty on MacOS Ventura</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/11-how-to-install-alacritty-on-macos-ventura/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 15:34:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/11-how-to-install-alacritty-on-macos-ventura/</guid>
      <description>Alacritty is a modern terminal emulator that comes with sensible defaults, but allows for extensive configuration.
Unlike iterm2 for MacOS, Alacritty doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any kind of GUI for it&amp;rsquo;s configuration. Everything can be done using a conf file.
Installing using HomebrewUse the following brew command in terminal:
$ brew install --cask alacritty Launching Alacritty When launching alacritty for the first time, there might be a pop up similar to - To fix this you can use the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Apps Using Terminal in Ubuntu 22.10</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/10-how-to-install-apps-using-terminal-in-ubuntu-22.10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 04:38:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/10-how-to-install-apps-using-terminal-in-ubuntu-22.10/</guid>
      <description>Using terminal is the easiest way to install apps in linux
Installing appsTo install apps use the following command:
$ sudo apt install packageName Replace packageName with the name of the package
Uninstalling appsUsing removeTo uninstall apps use the following command:
$ sudo apt remove packageNamudo/ Replace packageName with the name of the package
or
Using purge$ sudo apt purge packageName Replace packageName with the name of the package
Difference between remove &amp;amp; purgeThe primary difference being ‘remove‘ and ‘purge‘ is that ‘remove‘ only gets rid of the package leaving any configuration files untouched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add an Alias in Macos Terminal</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/09-how-to-add-an-alias-in-macos-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 18:36:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/09-how-to-add-an-alias-in-macos-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Zsh is the default MacOS Shell. So to add an alias, we need to make changes to the zsh config file that is .zshrc.
Open .zshrc.zshrc is typically present in the home folder ~/.zshrc
Adding aliasAdd the alias to the .zshrc in the following syntax
alias aliasName=&amp;#34;command&amp;#34; Source .zshrcAfter saving, source .zshrc using the following command in the Terminal
$ source ~/.zshrc </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Bash Script Executable</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/08-how-to-make-a-bash-script-executable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 12:31:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/08-how-to-make-a-bash-script-executable/</guid>
      <description>Bash scripts can be used to automate bash shell commands, they have the extention .sh. I personally use these to do some repetitive tasks like deploying a new post to this site.
To run a bash script you need to use the following command syntax in the command line:
sh ./address/scriptName.sh But the script is not executable by itself, to make it executable follow the following steps
1. Add approriate shebangFor bash add the following shebang at the top of the script</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Plugins in Neovim</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/06-how-to-install-plugins-in-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 10:52:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/06-how-to-install-plugins-in-neovim/</guid>
      <description>We are going to use a plugin manager &amp;lsquo;vim-plug&amp;rsquo; for installing &amp;amp; managing plugins in neovim.
The following tutorial is for Neovim &amp;amp; not for Vim.
Create ConfigCreate a directory for Neovim config if not already
mkdir ~/.config/nvim Create an init.vim file
touch ~/.config/nvim/init.vim Vim-plug installationcurl -fLo ~/.config/nvim/autoload/plug.vim --create-dirs https://raw.githubusercontent.com/junegunn/vim-plug/master/plug.vim Create a file for pluginsCreate a new file plugins.vim for organisation.
mkdir ~/.config/nvim/vim-plug touch ~/.config/nvim/vim-plug/plugins.vim Adding pluginsAdd the following to ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vscode Like Live Server for Terminal</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/04-vscode-like-live-server-for-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 10:38:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/04-vscode-like-live-server-for-terminal/</guid>
      <description>What is Live Server?Live Server lets the user to see the real time changes done in .html files in a browser.
Live Server in VS CodeIn Visual Studio Code, there&amp;rsquo;s a plugin &amp;lsquo;Live Server&amp;rsquo; which let&amp;rsquo;s the user host a local live server to see the changes in there html project.
live-serverlive-server is an npm package which basically sets up a live server.
RequirementsMust have node &amp;amp; npm installed.
InstallationRun the following command in the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Vim Is Just Better</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/03-why-vim-is-just-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 12:40:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/03-why-vim-is-just-better/</guid>
      <description>What is Vim?According to the Vim&amp;rsquo;s official website, Vim is a highly configurable text editor built to make creating and changing any kind of text very efficient. It is included as &amp;ldquo;vi&amp;rdquo; with most UNIX systems and with Apple OS X. Also it is free &amp;amp; opensource.
Vim features Its memory footprint is very low and is a terminal app. It is command centric. You can perform complex text related task with few commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add social media preview (WhatsApp card) to your website</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/02-how-to-add-social-media-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 23:07:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/02-how-to-add-social-media-preview/</guid>
      <description>You might have come across some websites that when shared on social media platforms like Twitter &amp;amp; WhatsApp shows a preview card of the website which typically includes an image and a short description of the page. This is accomplished with the use of OpenGraph protocol. This is used to add meta data to your websites.
How to add social media previewThis is done by adding OpenGraph meta tags to the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; tag of the HTML file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/01-my-first-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 11:51:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/01-my-first-blog/</guid>
      <description>The title of this page, as cliché as it may sound is true and with a lot of self persuasion I&amp;rsquo;m continuing to write. As this is the beginning of a new journey I would like to make this one about who I am, what are my expections and goals with this particular blog and what structure or kind of content would I be writing so let&amp;rsquo;s start with my basic introduction:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
