<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on Chaitanya&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2022 | Chaitanya Shahare</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 19:29:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Cramped to Comfy: My College Hostel Room Budget Desk Setup that Changed the Game</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/hostel-room-budget-desk-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 19:29:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/hostel-room-budget-desk-setup/</guid>
      <description>Desk setups are pretty important when you have to spend hours in front of a computer. This is especially true for a college student.&#xA;So, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing my Budget, Minimal Desk setup in my hostel room at the National Institute of Technology Srinagar (NITSRI).&#xA;Things to keep in mind As this is a hostel room setup can&amp;rsquo;t have anything expensive as it can be damaged and budget of course. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t occupy much space as hostel rooms are pretty small and you have to share them with others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Your Productivity: Create a Schedule with ChatGPT and Sync it with Google Calendar</title>
      <link>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/maximise-your-productivity-create-a-schedule-with-chatgpt-and-sync-it-with-google-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 15:00:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.chaitanyashahare.com/posts/maximise-your-productivity-create-a-schedule-with-chatgpt-and-sync-it-with-google-calendar/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionPlanning ahead is arguably the most important skill for being more productive. Nothing notable can be accomplished without a plan. A daily schedule can help you achieve your goals and remove the stress of wondering what to do next.&#xA;With a good plan and schedule, you can sit back and relax when it&amp;rsquo;s time to relax and get things done when you&amp;rsquo;ve planned it. You can be assured that you have adequate time for all your commitments.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
